帅哥，怎么样?
Hey,gorgeous! How's it going?
萤光灯下的脱水日本面
Dehydrated Japanese noodles under fluorescent lights.
我能有多好?
Does it get better than this?
问你一个问题 你目前没有约会的对象吧?
Question: Are you dating anyone?
我遇见一个和你是绝配的人
I met somebody who would be perfect for you.
绝配或许是个问题
Perfect might be a problem.
你若说共同独立或自我毁灭的话…
Had you said codependent or self-destructive....
-周六想要有个约会的对象吗? -当然，拜托了
-You want a date Saturday? -Yes,please.
他人帅
He is cute.
-而且风趣，他… -你说的是“他”?
-He's funny. He's -He's a he?
是的
Well,yeah.
糟了，我以为…
Oh,God! I just
你人品很好，上帝啊
You' re nice Oh,God.
很好,雪莉,我要到马桶去把自己冲掉
Good,Shelly. I' m gonna flush myself down the toilet now.
再见
Okay. Bye-bye.
六人行 第1季 第08集 （祖母）娜娜死了两回
The One Where Nana Dies Twice
听完后我没心情吃面了 这不荒谬吗?
It's hard to enjoy noodles after that. Is that ridiculous?
你能相信她会有这样的想法吗?
Can you believe she actually thought that?
能
Yeah.
我第一次见到你时 我以为你是
When I first met you,I thought maybe...
…可能…
... possibly...
…也许
...you might be.
你真的这样认为?
You did?
对，但后来你在菲比的生日会上 一直盯着我的胸部
You spent Phoebe's birthday party talking to my breasts...
…我想你大概不是吧
...so I figured maybe not.
你们第一次看见我时 也是这样认为?
Did any of the rest of you guys think that when you first met me?
-我是 -我也是
-I did. -I think so,yeah.
-我不是 -不，我也不这么认为
-Not me. -No,no,me neither.
虽然大学时代的苏珊・萨兰登这样认为
Although back in college,Susan Saladore did.
开什么玩笑?
You' re kidding.
-你有告诉她我不是吗? -没有
-Did you tell her I wasn't? -No.
因为我也想跟她约会
I wanted to go out with her too.
我告诉她你和伯尼・斯伯曼是一对
I told her you were seeing Bernie Spellman...
因为他也喜欢她
...who also liked her.
所以,这简直是太神奇了
Well,this is fascinating.
是什么原因?
So what is it about me?
我不知道 因为你既聪明又风趣
I don't know. You' re smart,you' re funny....
罗斯也是聪明又风趣 你们有想过他是吗?
So is Ross. Ever think that about him?
-是哦 -到底是为什么?
-Yeah,right! -What is it?
我也说不上来 但你就是有那种潜质
I don't know. You just You have a quality.
-没错 -是的.潜质
-Yes,exactly. -Yeah,a quality.
潜质?说得好 我还担心你们看不出呢
"A quality. " Good. I was worried you were gonna be vague about this.
我想对你应该有用
I think this is gonna work for you.
-你说什么？ -好吧,好吧
-Excuse me? -Sure,sure.
女人发现你没有威胁 就会敞开大门…
Women find you less threatening,they let their guards down...
…你就像一个偷偷摸摸的异性恋者
...you' re like a stealth heterosexual.
-瑞秋，是保罗从罗马打来的 -天啊，从罗马打来
-It's Paolo calling from Rome. -Oh,my God! Calling from Rome!
他从罗马打来 我也可以
So he's calling from Rome. I could do that.
我到罗马去就是了
Just gotta go to Rome.
莫妮卡，你爸打来的 你能长话短说吗?
Your Dad just beeped in. Can you make it quick?
我正和罗马通电话
I'm talking to Rome.
爸，怎么了?
Hey,Dad. What's up?
我的天
Oh,God.
罗斯，是外婆
Ross,it's Nana.
-你们还好吧? -嗨,爸爸
-How you doing? -Hey,Dad.
她的情况如何?
So how is she doing?
医生说只剩几小时了
The doctor says it's a matter of hours.
-妈,你还好吧? -我?我还好
-How are you,Mom? -Me? I' m fine,fine.
真高兴见到你们来
I' m glad you' re here.
-你的头发怎么了? -什么?
-What's with your hair? -What?
-看起来有点不同 -没什么变化呀
-What's different? -Nothing.
或许是这个缘故
Oh,maybe that's it.
-她真是令人难以置信 -放松点
-She's unbelievable. Her mother's -Okay,relax.
看来我们得在这儿待一段时间了
We' re gonna be here a while.
我们可以谈你男友和工作的事来盖住
We still have boyfriends and your career to cover.
我的老天
Oh,God!
她皮包里有发霉的钱币
The fuzzy little mints at the bottom of her purse.
真恶心
Yeah,they were gross.
你们知道我喜欢什么吗?
You know what I love?
她的人工袋糖
Her Sweet 'N Lows.
她总是从餐厅里偷走
How she was always stealing them from restaurants.
不只是餐厅,我们家也一样
Not just from restaurants,from our house.
盖勒太太
Mrs. Geller?
她看起来好小
She looks so small.
我知道
I know.
至少她现在有外公和菲力斯婶婶陪伴
Well,at least she's with Pop-Pop and Aunt Phylis now.
菲力斯婶婶死了?
Aunt Phylis is dead?
是的,大概有差不多六年了
Yeah,for like six years.
-我当时在哪里? -我们不要跑题,行不行?
Where were? Can we focus,please?
别了，外婆
Goodbye,Nana.
再见，外婆
Bye,Nana.
护士!
Nurse!
到底怎么回事?
What is going on?
护士说她已过世了
You know how the nurse said Nana had passed?
实际上不是
Well,she's not quite.
什么?
What?
她还没完全过世 她还活着，她回来了
She's not passed! She's present! She's back!
怎么回事?
What's going on?
她可能死了
She may have died.
她可能死了?
She may have died?
我们正等着消息
We're looking into it.
我进去看看
I'll go see.
这种事几乎不可能发生
This almost never happens.
现在，她过世了
Now she's passed.
我必须要知道
I just have to know,okay?
是我头发的问题?
Is it my hair?
对，正是你的头发
Yes,that's exactly what it is. It's your hair.
你有一头同性恋的头发
Yeah,you have homosexual hair.
她怎么样了?
So did she...?
两次
Twice.
-两次? -见鬼
-Twice? -Oh,that sucks.
-你们还好吧? -说不上来，好诡异
-You guys okay? -I don't know. It's weird.
我知道她已过世 但我感觉…
I know she's gone,but I just don't feel....
或许是因为她还没有
Maybe she's not really gone.
不，她过世了
No,no,she's gone.
我们检查了
We checked.
好多遍
A lot.
或许人不会真正过世
No,I mean,maybe no one ever really goes.
我妈死后,我偶尔…
Ever since my mom died,every now and then...
…会感觉她就在身旁
... I get this feeling that she's right here,you know?
还有黛比,我初中最要好的朋友
And Debbie,my friend from junior high...
在打迷你高尔夫时,被闪电击中
...got struck by lightning on a miniature golf course.
用那枝黄色铅笔时…
I always get this strong Debbie vibe...
…我总感到一股强烈的“黛比感应”
...when I use a little yellow pencil.
-我好想念她 -来，菲比
-I miss her. -Here,Pheebs.
你要吗?
Want this?
-谢谢 -不客气
-Oh,thanks. -Sure.
早上刚把她削好
I just sharpened her this morning.
我不信这一套
I don't believe any of that. When you' re dead...
人死了就是死了 死了就成了虫的食物
...you' re dead. You' re gone. You' re worm food.
钱德看起来像个同性恋对吧?
So Chandler looks gay,huh?
我不知道此人是谁 但绝对不是黛比
I don't know who this is,but it's not Debbie.
爸爸，我们需要做个决定
Dad,let's just make a decision.
你是对的，要把她埋在土里
You're right. It's going into the ground.
我们应该把基本的东西弄好
We should get the most basic thing.
“上面有白色薄片的，不受保护的波纹纤维板”
"The non-protective corrugated fiberboard with white laminate. "
爸爸，我们不能把外婆穿的像一只食肉鹦鹉
Dad,we can't bury Nana in a dresser from kea.
这就是你妈妈买了我的衣服的原因
This is why your mother buys my clothes.
我讨厌买东西，讨厌
I hate to shop. I hate it.
这是不是就像是
Isn't this more about the fact that...
一旦你作出决定，知道外婆真的走了一样
...once you decide,it's like acknowledging Nana's actually gone?
不是，我只是讨厌买东西
No,I really hate to shop.
-我以为要用密封的棺木 -这并不代表她不能看起来体面一点
-I thought it'd be a closed casket. -lt doesn't mean she can't look nice.
孩子，你想你能进去吗?
Sweetie,you think you can get in there?
当然可以
I don't see why not.
这是我的牙齿矫正器
Here's my retainer.
我在想…
I was just thinking...
-…我走的时候 -爸
-...when my time comes -Dad.
听我说
Listen to me.
我走的时候,我要海葬
When my time comes,I wanna be buried at sea.
什么?
You what?
我要海葬,好像挺有意思的
I wanna be buried at sea. It looks like fun.
什么叫“有意思”
Define "fun. "
那一天你们会玩得很开心的 你们会乘着船带着午餐…
Come on. You'll make a day of it. You'll get a boat,pack a lunch....
然后把你的尸体丢入大海 真是有意思
And then we throw your body in the water. Gee,that does sound fun.
每个人都自认为了解我 他们都说杰克太一成不变了
Everyone thinks they know me. Everyone says I'm so predictable.
或许我死后他们会说 海葬,哈?
Maybe after I'm gone,they'll say," Buried at sea? Huh? "
他们大概会这么说吧
That's probably what they'll say.
希望如此
I'd like that.
-美女 -嘿
-Hey,gorgeous. -Hey.
昨天的事我很抱歉
Look,l' m sorry about yesterday.
别担心,相信我 显然别人也犯了相同的错误
Don't worry. Apparently,other people have made the same mistake.
好吧,咻!
Okay. Phew!
为什么你认为我是?
So,what do you think it is about me?
我说不上来
I don't know what.
你就是有那种…
You just have...
-…潜质 -潜质，是哦
-...a quality. -A quality. Great.
真可惜，因为你和罗尔本来很登对
It's a shame. You and Lowell would've made a great couple.
罗尔?会计部门的罗尔 你觉得我们很配?
Lowell? Financial Services Lowell? That's who you saw me with?
有何不可?他很帅
What? He's cute.
是啊
Well,yeah.
他不像布莱恩
He's no Brian in Payroll.
布莱恩是不是…?
Is Brian?
我不知道，只是如果你想替我配对
I don't know. If you were gonna set me up...
我希望你会挑他
... I'd like to think it'd be with somebody like him.
我想你配不上布莱恩
Brian's a little out of your league.
对不起,你认为我配不上布莱恩?
Excuse me. You don't think I could get a Brian?
我绝对配得上他,相信我
Because I could get a Brian. Believe you me.
我真的配不上
I'm really not.
这一个?
This one?
我已让你们看过每件衣服
I've shown you every dress we have.
除非你们想让她永远穿着柠檬黄长裤
Unless you want her to spend eternity in a lemon-yellow pantsuit...
配上紫红色衣服
...go with the burgundy.
不论我们选什么 她都会说我们选错了
Whatever we pick,she'd say it's the wrong one.
没错，就选紫红色吧
Right. We'll go with the burgundy.
不错的选择，我要出来了
A fine choice. I'm coming out.
等等，还缺鞋子
Wait! We need shoes.
-这一双如何? -这是一双白天的鞋
-How about these? -That's really a day shoe.
她去的地方 大家都很会打扮吗?
Where she's going everyone else will be dressier?
能找鞋跟细一点的鞋吗?
Could we see something in a slimmer heel?
我找不到紫红色的晚鞋
I have nothing in an evening shoe in the burgundy.
不过有双银色的鞋或许适合
I can show you something silver that may work.
-不行，一定要紫红色 -除非我们另找一件套装
-No,it really should be burgundy. -Unless we go with a different dress.
不,等等,我看看
No,no,no. Watch this.
后面或许有
Wait,I may have something in the back.
天呀
Oh,my God.
你没事吧，孩子?
Is everything all right?
没事，只是外婆的东西
Just Nana's stuff.
各位如何?准备好了没?
You guys ready?
早上妈来电话叫我别扎头发
Mom called to tell me not to wear my hair up.
-我的耳朵并不是我最漂亮的部位吗? -有时候我认为是
-Know my ears aren't my best feature? -Some days it's all I can think about.
抱歉，我迟到了 我找不到我的“风度”（多加了一个b）
I' m sorry l' m late. I couldn't find my bearings.
你是指你的耳环?
You mean your earrings?
我刚说什么?
What did I say?
-你穿这一双? -对，保罗从意大利寄来的
-Are these the shoes? -Yes. Paolo sent them from ltaly.
我们这儿没卖鞋子的?
What? We don't have shoes here?
-早安，准备走了没? -穿上衣服后,我们是不是都好看许多?
-Morning. We ready to go? -Don't we look nice all dressed up?
这是废话对吧？
It's stuff like that,isn't it?
-刚刚的仪式简单而隆重 -可不是吗
-lt was a really beautiful service. -lt really was.
过来，心肝
Come here,sweetheart.
你该使用晚霜了
You know,I think it's time for you to start using night cream.
什么?
What?
没什么,只是你的外套听起来很像
布瑞特・马斯伯格（体育节目解说）
Nothing. Just that your coat sounds like Brent Musberger.
-瞧，巨人队对牛仔队 -你在葬礼时看足球赛?
-Check it out. Giants-Cowboys. -You're watching football at a funeral?
不，这还只是热身 我要在招待会上看比赛
No,it's the pre-game. I' m gonna watch it at the reception.
你真是个恶劣的人
You're a frightening,frightening man.
不，保罗送我的新鞋
Oh,no! My new Paolo shoes!
希望没坏
I hope they're not ruined.
多美好的一天啊
God,what a great day!
什么?我是指天气
What? Weather-wise.
我知道
I know.
空气，树木
The air,the trees.
即使外婆已过世,就好像…
Even though Nana's gone,there's something almost life
罗斯，你还好吧?罗斯…
Ross,are you okay?
我没事
No,l' m fine.
只是…
Just...
…我最大的梦魇终于成真,但是…
... having my worst fear realized,but....
别担心,我只是看看你是否肌肉痉挛
I' m just checking to see if the muscle's in spasm.
-怎么了? -你的皮带环掉了一个
-What? What is it? -You missed a belt loop.
是痉挛
Okay,it's in spasm.
来,孩子,我擦伤时都用这个
Here,sweetie. I took these when I had my gall thing accident.
妈，谢谢
Thanks,Mom.
抱歉
Sorry.
我叫安朵拉
Hi,l' m Andrea.
桃乐丝的女儿
I'm Dorothy's daughter.
我叫钱德,我不知道桃乐丝是谁
Hi,I'm Chandler,and I have no idea who Dorothy is.
看看谁出现了
Look who's up!
-感觉如何? -感觉好多了…
-How do you feel? -I feel great.
感觉好多了…感觉好多了…
I feel great. I feel great.
那些药丸可真有效
Wow,those pills really worked.
对，不是第一次那两颗 而是后来那两颗
Yeah. Not the first two,but the second two....
我爱你们大家
I love you guys.
你们是最棒的 我爱我的妹妹
You guys are the greatest. I love my sister.
我爱菲比
I love Pheebs.
你真好
That's so nice.
钱德，我爱你
I love you,man.
听着,如果你想当同志,就当吧
And listen,if you wanna be gay,be gay!
我不在乎
It doesn't matter to me.
你说对了
You were right.
我最爱你了
I do love you.
哦,罗斯,我也爱你
Oh,Ross. I love you too.
哦,不,我真的爱你
Oh,no,I really love you.
我也真的爱你
I really love you.
哦,你没有明白
Oh,you don't get it!
-那是什么? -只是个助听器
-What do you got there? -Just a hearing disability.
比分多少?
What's the score?
巨人队以17比14领先 第三节只剩3分钟结束
1 7-1 4,Giants. Three minutes to go in the third.
好极了
Beautiful!
菲比，能拿块饼干给我吗?
Pheebs,could you maybe hand me a cracker?
你外婆一定不喜欢的
Your grandmother would've hated this.
当然，这是她的葬礼
Sure. What with it being her funeral and all.
不，我听到的是
No,I'd be hearing about...
“我为何没有蜜汁火腿?”
...why didn't I get the honey-glazed ham.
或是我买的花不够，或者她会说
Or I didn't spend enough on flowers. Or she'd say:
“何必花那么多钱，我死了不需要花”
"Why waste your money? I don't need flowers,l' m dead. "
口气像外婆
That sounds like Nana.
知道和批评你每句话的人…
Do you know what it's like to grow up...
…在一起生活是什么滋味?
...with someone who is critical of every single thing you say?
我可以想像
I can imagine.
告诉你，我希望你妈会成为…
It's a wonder your mother turned out...
…一个像她一样乐观、积极的人
...to be the positive,life-affirming person she is.
真是个奇迹
That is a wonder.
妈，告诉我 如果可以重来
So tell me something,Mom. If you had to do it all over again...
如果此时她在这儿
... I mean,if she was here right now...
你会告诉她吗?
...would you tell her?
告诉她什么?
T ell her what?
她如何使你抓狂 挑剔每一件事
How she drove you crazy,picking on every little detail.
例如你的头发
Like your hair,for example.
我不懂你在说什么
I'm not sure I know what you're getting at.
难道你不认为说出实话 情况会改善吗?
Would things have been better if you'd just told her the truth?
不
No.
我认为某些事最好还是不要说
Some things are better left unsaid.
和睦相处比较好
It's nicer when people just get along.
再来些酒吗？
More wine?
我也这么认为
Oh,I think so.
你戴这副耳环真好看
Those earrings look really lovely on you.
谢谢
Thank you.
你给我的
They're yours.
其实是外婆的
Actually,they were Nana's.
真叫人难过
Now l' m depressed!
比刚才还难过
Even more than I was.
哦,快看,我的一年级照片
Oh,look. My first grade picture.
请略过恐龙蛋T恤衫
Please ignore the Dy-no-mite T -shirt.
-这个光屁股的是谁? -那个人就是我
-Hey,who's this little naked guy? -That little naked guy would be me.
瞧那个小东西
Look at the little thing!
对，那是我的小弟弟
Yes,fine. That is my penis.
成熟点行吗?
Can we be grownups now?
那些人是谁?
Who are those people?
-可把我问倒了 -中间那一个是外婆
-Got me. -That's Nana right there in the middle.
我看看
Yeah,let's see.
“我和大伙儿在爪哇乔家”
" Me and the gang at Java Joe's. "
莫妮卡,你和你外婆长得一模一样 当时她几岁?
You look just like your grandmother. How old was she?
1939年…39年
Let's see," 1 939. "
24或25岁
Twenty-four,twenty-five.
他们好像玩得很开心
It looks like a fun gang.
看…光屁股的莫妮卡
Look,look,look! I got Monica naked!
我看看
Let me see!
不，还是我
No,no. That would be me again.
我在尝试新事物
I'm just trying something.
罗尔
Hey,Lowell.
钱德
Oh,hey,Chandler.
会计部门的情况如何?
So how's it going in Financial Services?
就像是狂欢节最后一天没有纸糊的头(一团乱)
It's like Mardi Gras without the papier-mache heads.
你呢?
How about you?
好的，听着…
Good. Good. Listen...
我不知道雪莉如何对你说我这个人…
...I don't know what Shelly told you about me,but...
…但是我不是
... I' m not.
我知道，我也是这样告诉她的
I know. That's what I told her.
真的?
Really?
你看得出来?
So you can tell?
差不多吧 我们有某种…雷达
Pretty much. Most of the time. We have a kind of radar.
这么说你认为我…
So you don't think I have...
…没那种潜质
...a quality?
代表男同志发言 我得说没有
Speaking for my people,I'd have to say no.
对了,你朋友布莱恩,他是
By the way,your friend Brian,from Payroll? He is.
-他是? -而且你配不上他
-He is? -And way out of your league.
我配不上他
Out of my league!
我可以得到布莱恩 只要我愿意就能得到他
I could get a Brian. If I wanted to get a Brian,I could get a Brian.
你好,布莱恩
Hey,Brian.